

LE THI NGOC THAO

+84 366 267 055

lethingocthao1510@gmail.com

Nguyen Thien Thuat, District 3, Ho Chi Minh

Experience working in the field of accounting and auditing (Big 4) with a strong motivation to contribute. Fundamental knowledge of corporate finance, accounting, auditing, financial analysis, and internal control. Good organizational skills, dynamic, honest, with a firm commitment accompanied by focus and work ethics. Able to work well in a team environment or independently.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ONPOINT CO.,LTD Sep 2024 - Present

Senior AR Accountant Excecutives

- As a member of the accounting team, responsible for managing and monitoring customer debts, ensuring that debts are collected on time and accurately in the E-commerce environment, working with major brands such as Shopee, Lazada, Nutifood, Obagi, DKSH, and others...
- Perform timely and accurate reconciliation of financial data from business users and accounting systems to prepare comprehensive Brand reconciliation reports matching with contract term.
- Provide the tracking status of pending with clear root cause and action plan for Commercial Directors and Management per schedule required.
- Monitor accounts receivable and follow up on per lead time and no overdue unbilled and billed to ensure timely collection.
- Develop and implement effective collection strategies to minimize overdue accounts
- Control and maintain of accounting system including Accounts Receivable, Monthly P&L of group brand
- Prepare monthly revenue report and regular reports on the status of accounts receivable collection, including aging reports, customer payment status, and overdue receivables
- Perform financial analysis, analyze business performance by Power BI, provide actionable suggestions for improvement, and issue early warnings on potential financial risks.

ERNST & YOUNG VIET NAM LIMITED

Mar 2022 - Sep 2024

Audit Associates

- Planned, conducted financial audit to ensure financial statements were fairly presented in accordance with local GAAP and Group accounting policies.
- Tested internal controls to ensure their effectiveness, prepared comprehensive reports on audit findings, including the material misstatements, weaknesses of internal controls and recommendations on improvement of internal controls.
- Performed audit working papers to ensure financial statements were fairly presented in accordance with local GAAP, Group accounting policies and IFRS (IFRS 9, IFRS 16)
- Analyzing financial reports to assess the performance and financial health of a business. Understanding of important financial indicators such as ROE, ROA, debt-to-equity ratio, etc.
- Exposure to various types of businesses to understand different business models, from small and medium enterprises to large corporations
- Have worked with some big customers with various industries:
 - Loc Troi Group Joint Stock Company (LTG): top company of agri-business (rice, pesticides)
 - Olam Group: agri-business, manufacturing food-rice, coffee, beans
 - Dat Xanh Group JSC, Hung Thinh Land JSC: top company of real estate industry

MAZARS VIETNAM CO., LTD

Feb 2021 - May 2021

Accounting Intern

- Support the Accounting team for monthly closing activities for entities, including preparation/posting of entries, reconciliation of accounts, etc.
- Support preparation of statutory accounts and tax filing, including VAT and WHT.
- Support issuing and printing sales invoices for the filling process, preparing input VAT reports, updating accounting transactions for analysis
- Skill gained: Learn more about standard accounting, tax, and basic steps to prepare tax declarations and financial statements; Carefulness; Teamwork; Logical thinking

EDUCATION

University of Economics and Law

2018 - 2022

· Bachelor of Auditing

SAPP EDUCATION JSC

2023 - Present

• CFA level 1 (Chartered Financial Analyst)

KEY COMPETENCIES

Process improvement Financial modeling Risk management Power BI Financial planning & analysis Reporting under local GAAP, IFRS and Group accounting policies Strong interpersonal skills Proactive and self-motivated Critical thinking skills

ACHIVEMENTS

- Outstanding performance for 2 years at Ernst & Young Vietnam Company Limited
- Talent management Program of Ernst & Young Company Limited

FURTHER INFORMATION

Experience in audit with near three years in the 1 in 4 of largest in the field of auditing of Vietnam. With that experience I believe that I had a huge ability to take responsibility as assigned. I am looking forward to learning more about the position and discuss further with you in an interview in the near future.